Giselle Sanchez

Email: gisellesanchez@pursuit.org | Mobile: (347)300-5843

https://github.com/gsanchez13 | http://www.linkedin.com/in/giselle-sanchez13

SKILLS

Technical

Javascript, HTML, CSS, React, Node.js, SQL, Redux, Postgres, GitHub

PROJECTS

Ethic Attire

In alignment with the UN's sustainable goals for 2020, this application aims to make an impact in the fashion industry by providing a simple clothing tracking system, education on materials, and resources for future purchases to consumers.

- Worked collaboratively with peers during a week-long Hackathon event.
- Curated frontend that displays individual clothing items belonging to a user, developed with React libraries, and implemented materialize styling frameworks to create a simple and appealing UI for better user experience.
- Created polished SQL queries for specific data return in routes.

Marathoner

Social application that allows users to interact with one another based on television shows they are currently watching.

- Uses RESTful API requests with SQL queries to obtain information of programs.
- Formats client-friendly frontend with React components.

Ghibli Moviepage

A webpage that uses the Studio Ghibli API to make network requests and display them to users, as well as a form to add comments to the movies page.

- Asynchronous functionality as well as DOM manipulation are used to allow a client to view movies created by Studio Ghibli and leave reviews on individual pages.
- Custom CSS file adds attractive background and simple navigation.

EXPERIENCE

NorthEast Community Bank

New York, NY

Customer Service Associate

June 2018 - Present

- Manage clientele's finances through extensive record keeping, active customer service and account alterations with use of MISER online banking software.
- Use a cross-departmental support system to resolve any consumer problems or inquiries on a daily basis, while also handling cash in terms of shipments, ATM and customer disbursements.
- Maintain a secure system by establishing relationships with patrons through functional communication and strict protocols, such as FDIC and BSA regulations.

Niketown

New York, NY

Part-time Athlete

Feb 2016 - July 2017

- Provided premium service to all consumers while relating to athletic knowledge through focused interactions and using company service ethos to fully create a positive experience for all consumers.
- Strived towards meeting store goals, such as higher conversion rates based on daily 2000+ foot traffic and a minimum of 2.5 units per transaction.

EDUCATION

Pursuit

Long Island City, NY

12-month Full Stack Web intensive coding program with a 9% acceptance rate.

June 2019 - Present

Baruch College - Zicklin School of Business

New York, NY

Bachelor of Business Administration in International Business, Minors in Marketing and Spanish

Jan 2016 - May 2018